## VENKATA SAI HARSHAVARDHAN SANAKA

E-mail: vsanaka@asu.edu | Phone: (480)-803-5345 | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/harshavardhan-s-v-s-8b7177213/

#### **CAREER SUMMARY:**

Worked in IT sector with 1 year of experience. I'm passionate in learning new technologies, problem solving and enjoy collaboratively working with teams. I am also a quick learner and pick up the knowledge and performs the task efficiently. I am a self-possessed person who can work in an independent unsupervised environment as well as in a group environment.

#### **EDUCATION:**

**Information Technology (M.S)** Dec 2022

Ira A. Fulton Schools of Engineering at Arizona State University, USA. GPA: 4.11/4.00

Computer Science and Engineering (B.E)

Sept 2020 R.M.K Engineering college affiliated Anna university, India. GPA: 3.00/4.00

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

**Programming Languages:** C/C++, Python, Java, JavaScript.

Front-End: HTML, CSS, React.JS, Bootstrap.

Tools: Flask, Discord API, GitHub, IBM, Cloud, Tableau.

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

OS: IBM, Mac OS, Windows, Linux/Unix

Strong familiarity with G-suite, Microsoft office (Excel, Access, Word, PowerPoint, etc.), Zoom, Slack, Trello, Outlook,

Technical Documentation, Verification Testing & Prototyping.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

# Software Developer - Stealth Startup.

Aug 2020-Jul 2021

- Developed different backend services (API's) using Python Programming language.
- Extensively used pandas, NumPy, SQL for data processing, analysis, and visualizations.
- Skilled in manual and automated testing of applications and creating testing scenarios.
- Proficient in writing SQL queries using MySQL, MS SQL.
- Hands-on experience in executing MONGO DB general queries and aggregate queries.
- Develop products/features independently by writing scalable, efficient, and maintainable code
- Extensive experience in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).
- Actively participate in Sprint planning and execution.

#### Intern - Aurobindo pharma Ltd.

Jan 2019-Apr 2019

- Intern in the ÎBM lotus project in the Aurobindo pharma Ltd.
- Maintained the user database and security of the project.
- Worked on SQL basic queries and aggregation queries.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

## Library Aide III: (West Trust at High Density Collection in ASU)

*Oct 2021-Now* 

• Looking through the contents of the library items, sometimes page by page, to inspect the condition of the item. (Attention to details and ability to perform sustained repetitive tasks independently.)

• Using computer programs, such as Microsoft Excel or Access, to track the receipt and condition of numerous library items.

## RESEARCH AND PAPER PRESENTATIONS:

Crop prediction system using machine learning algorithm - (Advisor: Dr.A. Thilagavathi) Jun 2020 published in Journal of Xidian University, ISSN No: 1001-2400, Volume-14 Issue-6.

Tamil text detection in videos using Gradient Vector Flow and Fuzzy C-Means -Advisor: Dec 2019 (Dr.J.T. Anita Rose) Published in International Journal of Engineering and Advanced Technology (IJEAT), ISSN: 2249 – 8958, Volume-9 Issue-2.

## **RELEVANT PROJECTS:**

# **Overseas Studies**

Fall 2021

With the help of Angular 9, node js and Mongo DB, Couchbase database, designed an application provides information to users about the universities ranking, tuition fees, acceptances percentage, course detail, etc. Written the reports and technical specifications based on project requirements. Leveraged SQL queries to store, retrieve and analyze the data and generated the reports using data visualization techniques

**Trading Application** *Spring 2021* 

- Built a Trading assistant application which provide the certain recommendations based on different parameters and different visualization of portfolio and trends in the stock market.
- Implemented backend services by developing relative APIs.
- Integrated the APIs data with the Frontend mobile and web applications.
- Built smart video, personalized news generation, social platform features resulting in the user engagement into the application.
- Followed Agile methodology to improve project key processes and culture within the team and drove scrum ceremonies.

• Written the requirement documents and technical specification document based on customer requirements.

# **Crop prediction system**

Fall 2020

It is used to weather forecasting and predicting the amount of rainfall that will occur in an area can be very tedious using Machine Learning. Also, it is an effective way to guide the farmer for better plant seeding. Due to advancement and availability of technology, usage of mobile and web applications has been increased ex-potentially.

# **Home Automation**

Fall 2019

With the help of Arduino programming, designed a device which controls home appliances using Wi-Fi and Bluetooth modules. The home appliances are controlled through a mobile application on the user's mobile.

Movie Analyzer

Spring 2018

Coded a simple neural network to recognize the text present on the image of a movie poster and analyze the various contents of the movie and visualize it as a pie chart using pandas. Also, with the NLP techniques included it is possible to search the queries related to the movie and get the results.

# **CERTIFICATIONS:**

- Coursera (Developing AI applications on azure),
- Coursera (Getting started with AWS machine learning).
- Udemy (The web developer bootcamp),
- Coursera (Perform sentiment Analysis with scikit-learn).
- Certified in Business English Vantage (council of Europe level B1) from Cambridge university.